# **ALLEN LI**

Beijing, China | 18210473070 | allen.li.salesforce@gmail.com in-

## **SUMMARY**

A certificated salesforce developer with 6+ years experience & 4×Certifications for salesforce project architect, salesforce solution consultant, force.com development, large system integration with SAP(IC, BW, etc.). I have worked on 10+ salesforce projects and implemented lots of business requirements for various industries.

I'm passionate for my salesforce career and ready to take any challenges. As a big fan of salesforce and web front-end technologies, I built Metaforce which is an amazing salesforce development/deployment tool to help sf developers speed up salesforce work.

# **Technical Specialties:**

- Salesforce standard function configuration(Sales/Service Cloud) | Excellent
- Salesforce force.com Development(Apex/Pages/Batch, etc) | Excellent
- Salesforce API Integration with SAP BW/IC/Finance system(SOAP, REST, Bulk) | Excellent
- Salesforce Metadata & System Migrations (Tooling API, Metadata API, Ant) | Excellent
- Continuous Integration(Jenkins + Github/GitLab/Bitbucket + Ant Migration Tool) | Excellent
- Salesforce Lightning Experience & Application & Component Development | Good
- Full Stack Web Development( HTML/CSS/JS + JQuery + Bootstrap + AngularJs + NodeJs + Grunt) | Good

# **Project Experience:**

- Team Lead, Technical Consultant, SCRUM Development as Master
- Salesforce Development Flow Control, Code Version Control (GIT)
- Collaborate with global team members and managers

#### **Certifications:**

- Salesforce Certified Administrator
- Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder
- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I (401)
- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer II (501)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Sony Global Information System** 

Salesforce Solution Technical Leader & Team Leader | 2014.12 - 2016.01 & 2017.03 - Now

**Projects: Sony VIP System | Audit Tracker** 

Responsibilities:

- Analyze and Provide technical solutions for business requirement, assist solution manager to build better solutions to solve business problems
- Provide all integration scheme and technical details between Salesforce and SAP(BW, IC, iShop, Finance, etc.)
- Build project plan and break down development tasks, control project progress with GIT
- Collaborate with Dev & Global team to solve user ticket & technical issues & business feedback
- Apex/Visualforce/Interface Development

# Tujia

Salesforce Senior Consultant | 2016.01 - 2017.2

**Projects: Tujia | TuYuan Salesforce Systems** 

Responsibilities:

- Manage business requirement and TUJIA Sales Organization
- Implements customized function to track sales activities
- Design new salesforce system based on company business flow
- Migrate system and data between salesforce organizations
- System Integration with OA system to exchange contract and payment information

# Meginfo

**Salesforce Developer** | 2012.06 – 2014.12

**Projects: WhiteHat | Snapbi | Costume Manager** 

Responsibilities:

- Customize portal site and implement business requirements with visual force page
- Improve customer service level with Web to Lead, Web to Case, Live Agent, Salesforce Entitlement Management
- Optimize internal salesforce system with front-end technologies (Bootstrap, JQuery, Html + Css, Grunt)

# **KEY PROJECTS EXPERIENCE**

# **SONY VIP Project & Audit Tracker**

The Salesforce VIP System is a core system to help global business to build pricing and plan market

## **Tujia & TuYuan Sales Management System**

<u>Tujia Sales Management System</u> is a standard sales system. For sales reps, they can manage their customers and opportunities more efficient (Account, Opportunity, Contract, etc); For sales managers, they can check all sales data and get accurate forecast data in real time (Approval, Report, Forecast); For finance, they can manage payment/pending payment and get actual revenues of company.

### **eBest SFA PRODCUT**

eBest SFA is an ipad application to help sales to visit client, track KPI, arrange tasks. And sales managers can use salesforce system to make sales plan and KPI targets, then assign them to sales and check sales reports. All backend data are analyzed and stored in salesforce automatically, then sync to end device.

#### **WhiteHat Customer Portal**

WhiteHat Customer Portal is an internal customer community to provide internal document review/download, case management.

# **CostumeManager Project**

CostumeManager is a highly customized portal site to help internal client to place order for different costumes.

# Metaforce – a lightweight salesforce IDE | Personal Project

<u>Metaforce</u> is a lightweight salesforce IDE. Based on front-end technologies, Metaforce builds a modern and elegant UI to provide powerful features (Login Management, Code Editor, Deployment and Test) for salesforce development.

# Salesforce Deployer - Personal Project

Salesforce Deployer provides a quite easy way to login and deploy salesforce metadata quickly.

#### **EDUCATION**

Luoyang Normal University | Bachelor's degree | Computer Science | 2008 – 2012